MATT FITZPATRICK

T 314.680.1370 matt@50inthe314.com 50inthe314.com

Marketing professional, specializing in brand management and content marketing through digital channels including social media, search, and email. Expertise in strategy and development, asset execution, content production, and analysis of marketing campaigns. Able to develop unique marketing opportunities for brands and products while keeping the strategy and scope of the project in mind. Adapts well to changing targets, trends, and technology.

EXPERIENCE

DIGITAL MARKETING COORDINATOR, SAINT LOUIS UNIVERSITY, ST. LOUIS, MO JANUARY 2014 - PRESENT

- Lead digital marketing efforts, email, and social media campaigns for the John Cook School of Business.
- Implemented content marketing strategies and calendars. Organically increased audience 40% and reach 85%.
- Create and mange content for SLU's digital channels, including blogs, op-eds, press releases, and video content.
- Increased site traffic by 20% in 2014, with peak increases in social, email, and organic search traffic.
- Introduced social media to our digital marketing spend. Implemented Facebook and LinkedIn promoted posts, gained above average interactions and click-through-rates, and tracked conversions for our MBA program.
- Manage multiple vendors, work with both internal teams and outside agencies to expand marketing efforts.
- Maintain digital brand standards and website, focus on Content Creation, SEO, and conversion analytics.

ACCOUNT / MARKETING MANAGER, THE ABLE FEW, ST. LOUIS, MO NOVEMBER 2012 - NOVEMBER 2013

- Managed marketing for digital firm, including B2B efforts, social media, press releases, and event planning.
- Worked in a continuous release cycle, where many hands were on a single project and concerted contact with the client was required to maintain the expected level of accuracy and excellence.
- Developed business plans, site maps, and feature release timelines for web applications that have been featured at South By Southwest, Mashable.com, and other tech events and publications.

ACCOUNT MANAGER, CTM MEDIA GROUP, ST. LOUIS, MO

OCTOBER 2011 - NOVEMBER 2012

- Managed over 400 traditional and digital advertising placements for an array of clients, from tourist attractions and hotels to athletic teams and arenas, Fortune 500 companies, and nightlife spots.
- Introduced a new digital marketing medium to the St. Louis area. Facilitated placement in high end hotels and premium attractions. Increased digital reach in the St. Louis area to 2.5 million visitors annually.
- Created and presented analytical reports and research studies for our clients, showing where their marketing plan succeeded and giving insight on how to improve when needed.

PROJECT MANAGER AND DESIGNER, 50 IN THE 314 (FREELANCE CONSULTANCY) JANUARY 2010 - PRESENT

- Consultant / Designer / Digital Manager for area advertising agencies, startup businesses, and charities.
- Went one-on-one to discover needs, develop strategies, and execute digital and traditional marketing plans.
- Worked with brands ranging from high-end liquor and retail stores to non-for-profits and political campaigns.

CONSUMER HOSPITALITY REP. ANHEUSER-BUSCH. ST. LOUIS. MO SEPTEMBER 2006 - SEPTEMBER 2011

- Acted as brand ambassador for guests of Anheuser-Busch at the St. Louis Tour Center.
- Led tours of the brewery complex, educating visitors about the Anheuser-Busch brand and their portfolio.
- Coordinated projects among the staff, kept programs and day to day tasks running smoothly and efficiently.
- Promoted to Guest Service Specialist in fall of 2008.

PROFICIENCIES

- Digital Marketing Analytics (Google), Salesforce, Email (Mailchimp), Social Managers (Hootsuite, Radian6).
- Media Buying AdSense, AdWords, Social Media including Facebook, LinkedIn, Twitter, Instagram.
- Media Production Expertise in Photoshop, Illustrator & InDesign, proficient in Final Cut Pro.
- Development Full Wordpress Builds, Read and Write CSS, PHP & Ruby, Operates well in most CMS's.

EDUCATION

WEBSTER UNIVERSITY - ST. LOUIS, MO
BA - ADVERTISING AND MARKETING COMMUNICATIONS
SAINT LOUIS UNIVERSITY - ST. LOUIS, MO
MBA - MARKETING

GRADUATED WITH HONORS, MAY 2010

COMPLETION, 2017